<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mathematics on S. Verona Lišková</title>
    <link>https://sverona.dev/tags/mathematics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mathematics on S. Verona Lišková</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sverona.dev/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refurbishing an old Twitter bot</title>
      <link>https://sverona.dev/blog/amazing-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sverona.dev/blog/amazing-graphs/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago Numberphile released a series of videos concerning sequences in the OEIS with pretty plots. Inspired, I wrote a little Twitter bot that tweets out two such plots each day. I even got a follow from 3Blue1Brown. It was a wonderful source of dopamine for a while.
Because I hacked the thing together in a dayYou can check out the source code, if you&amp;rsquo;re okay with your eyes melting out of your skull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>\(\pi\) and \(e\) and the GCD</title>
      <link>https://sverona.dev/blog/gcd-ln/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sverona.dev/blog/gcd-ln/</guid>
      <description>While doing some research for my Project Euler post, I found myself drawn to something else that blew my mind in high school &amp;mdash; the connection between the greatest common divisor and the Riemann zeta function.
For those of you just joining us:
The greatest common divisor of two nonzero integers is the largest positive number that divides them both. The Riemann zeta function is the series \[\zeta(s) = \sum_{n = 1}^\infty \frac1{n^s} = \frac1{1^s} + \frac1{2^s} + \frac1{3^s} + \cdots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler 1-100 in 49 hours</title>
      <link>https://sverona.dev/blog/project-euler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sverona.dev/blog/project-euler/</guid>
      <description>Project Euler is how I taught myself Python in high school, and so I find it incredibly nostalgic. It took 13-year-old me a lot of Googling and a few months to get through the first 100 problems. Why 100 specifically? Because I wanted to write this post honestly and those are the ones I&amp;rsquo;m allowed to talk about without them locking my account or something.
10-odd years and a graduate degree later, I decided to come back and solve them as fast as I could.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Generalizations of Classical Integer Sequences Arising in Combinatorial Representation Theory</title>
      <link>https://sverona.dev/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sverona.dev/thesis/</guid>
      <description>Abstract There exists a natural correspondence between the bases for a given finite-dimensional representation of a complex semisimple Lie algebra and a certain collection of finite edge-colored ranked posets, laid out by Donnelly, et al. in, for instance, [Donnelly 2003]. Robert G. Donnelly. Extremal properties of bases for representations of semisimple Lie algebras. Journal of Algebraic Combinatorics, 17, 2003. In this correspondence, the Serre relations on the Chevalley generators of the given Lie algebra are realized as conditions on coefficients assigned to poset edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dual simplex method, an introduction</title>
      <link>https://sverona.dev/blog/dual-simplex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sverona.dev/blog/dual-simplex/</guid>
      <description>The primal simplex method provides an algorithmic means for solving linear programs (hereinafter LPs.) This document motivates, defines, and applies the so-called dual simplex method, a slight variant which is useful for performing post hoc sensitivity analysis on LPs solved by the simplex method.
The primal simplex method In this section, we review the three steps of the usual primal method, following [Hillier-Lieberman],Frederick S. Hillier and Gerald J. Lieberman, Introduction to operations research, 10th ed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
